<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>usability on USABLE Tools</title>
    <link>https://squiggy.github.io/ut/tags/usability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in usability on USABLE Tools</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 15:01:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://squiggy.github.io/ut/tags/usability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting High-Risk Tech Users: A Movement for Usability</title>
      <link>https://squiggy.github.io/ut/blog/2016-07-06-protecting-high-risk-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 15:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://squiggy.github.io/ut/blog/2016-07-06-protecting-high-risk-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connecting developers with users improves tools for human rights defenders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Janvier Hakizimana has a radical idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Governments and large global bodies like the United Nations subsidize new medications to fight disease. Why not also subsidize the adaptation of technology so that it can meet the needs of local communities?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adaptation — making tech tools more open, accessible, and customizable — matters in Janvier’s line of work. He works to support human rights defenders in the East and Horn of Africa who need secure tools to document and report human rights violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://squiggy.github.io/ut/images/blog/usability-secure-apps-screen readers_Credit_Mariel Garcia M.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Testing the usability of secure apps through screen readers, at a USABLE training in Mexico. Credit: Mariel Garcia&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Testing the usability of secure apps through screen readers, at a USABLE training in Mexico. Credit: Mariel Garcia M&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a tool can’t adapt to local conditions — when it is entirely reliant on an internet connection, for example, users in low-connectivity areas may not be able to use it on a broad scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relying on a hodge-podge of tools that each does one thing well makes work inefficient. Worse, relying on tools that aren’t secure puts high-risk communities in danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Janvier supports human rights defenders, in part as a trainer for USABLE, a project designed to connect high-risk users of digital security and communications tools with the developers who make those tools, in order to make the tools usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, USABLE will hold its first UX Forum in San Francisco, bringing digital security trainers and activists from Africa, Latin America, Eastern Europe and the Middle East with developers in the center of US tech development, for three days of hands-on collaboration. USABLE’s focus on human-centered design focuses the process on the real-world needs of activists working on sexual orientation and gender identity rights, media, democracy, and human rights in challenging and threatening environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>