<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personas on USABLE Tools</title>
    <link>https://usable.tools/personas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personas on USABLE Tools</description>
    <image>
  <link>https://usable.tools</link>
  <title>USABLE Tools</title>
  <url>https://usable.tools/images/logo.svg</url>
  <description>USABLE.tools</description>
</image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:50:48 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://usable.tools/personas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh: &#34;Habibur Rahman Sujon&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/bd_sujon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/bd_sujon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habibur is in his twenties and identifies as a &lt;strong&gt;Muslim gay&lt;/strong&gt; man. He lives in a small town where he must constantly hide his sexuality. Recently, Habibur went to Dhaka, the capital of Bangladesh, to attend a party for gay men. Police &lt;strong&gt;raided&lt;/strong&gt; the party and he and some of his friends were &lt;strong&gt;arrested&lt;/strong&gt;. The police outed them as gay men in front of the media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habibur has an &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;anonymous&amp;rdquo; Facebook profile&lt;/strong&gt; that he uses to connect with other gay men. He is an active member of a closed Facebook group for gay Bangladesh men. He often &lt;strong&gt;attends events&lt;/strong&gt; that are posted in this group. Many people do not have access to a smart phone in his remote village, so he relies on Facebook groups to stay connected to other people in the LGBT community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habibur needs to be able to &lt;strong&gt;connect&lt;/strong&gt; with other members of the LGBT community, without fearing for his safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is interested in learning more about how to &lt;strong&gt;safely&lt;/strong&gt; use online dating tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habibur&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;identity was revealed&lt;/strong&gt; when he was &lt;strong&gt;arrested&lt;/strong&gt; during the raid of a party. Bullying and social harassment increased significantly following this incident, particularly within his university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LGBT people are extremely &lt;strong&gt;vulnerable&lt;/strong&gt; when using social media or dating applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the risk mitigation materials that currently exist are only available in English. Habibur only speaks Bangla and therefore has &lt;strong&gt;limited resources&lt;/strong&gt; available to protect himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habibur owns a smart phone and knows how to use &lt;strong&gt;mobile applications&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He understands the basics of the Internet and he is able to &lt;strong&gt;send and receive emails&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I &lt;strong&gt;safely navigate&lt;/strong&gt; Facebook groups and dating applications for the LGBT
community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there &lt;strong&gt;risk mitigation materials&lt;/strong&gt; available in my native language of Bangla?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh: &#34;Tabassum&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/bd_tabassum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/bd_tabassum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabassum identifies as a &lt;strong&gt;lesbian&lt;/strong&gt; and has recently become an active voice for the rights of the LGBT community in Bangladesh. During the day, she works as a clerk at a local bank. She volunteers at an &lt;strong&gt;unregistered&lt;/strong&gt; LGBT rights organization. She also works with other activist groups for local and international &lt;strong&gt;advocacy&lt;/strong&gt;. She is out to a few of her friends, but not to her colleagues or family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to conduct meetings with other LGBT activists and the community, Tabassum needs to rely heavily on &lt;strong&gt;messaging applications&lt;/strong&gt; like Facebook Messenger and WhatsApp. She also uses her personal email regularly to communicate with ally organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabassum warnts to &lt;strong&gt;advance the LGBT rights movement&lt;/strong&gt; in Bangladesh by repealing Section 377.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also wants to &lt;strong&gt;raise awareness&lt;/strong&gt; and implement sensitization programs designed to create an accepting and inclusive society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homosexuality is &lt;strong&gt;illegal&lt;/strong&gt; in Bangladesh and LGBT activists can be &lt;strong&gt;arrested&lt;/strong&gt; by authorities according to Section 377 of the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been reports that activists are under &lt;strong&gt;digital surveillance&lt;/strong&gt; from both the government and religious militant groups. These activists are being &lt;strong&gt;tracked&lt;/strong&gt; through social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabassum has a strong peer activist &lt;strong&gt;network for support&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She knows which communication tools use &lt;strong&gt;encryption&lt;/strong&gt; and which do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She always meets other activists in &lt;strong&gt;public places&lt;/strong&gt; or a &lt;strong&gt;secure home&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I know if I am under &lt;strong&gt;surveillance&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I stop information from being &lt;strong&gt;leaked&lt;/strong&gt; to other people?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China: &#34;L. N.&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/cn-ln/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/cn-ln/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L.N. is in her early 20s, and is outgoing and charismatic. She lives in a major metropolitan area in &lt;strong&gt;mainland China&lt;/strong&gt;, and is a recent college graduate with many social connections; fluent in Cantonese and Mandarin, and proficient in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L. N. is a key member of an active &lt;strong&gt;women’s rights group&lt;/strong&gt; in China that has gained national and international media attention for some of its activities. She is committed to activism aimed at &lt;strong&gt;promoting the social and cultural change&lt;/strong&gt; necessary to bring about &lt;strong&gt;equal rights for women in China&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has come &lt;strong&gt;under pressure&lt;/strong&gt; to get married. Her resistance to this this pressure found expression in several videos that she co-produced with her group and posted on WeChat. These &lt;strong&gt;videos were widely shared&lt;/strong&gt; and led to a larger conversation throughout social media on the topic of women’s place in Chinese society. This attention has caused L.N., as well as members of the rights group, to come under &lt;strong&gt;closer scrutiny&lt;/strong&gt; by the authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing ability to speak freely and &lt;strong&gt;advocate&lt;/strong&gt; for women&amp;rsquo;s rights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintaining &lt;strong&gt;social connections&lt;/strong&gt; with network of fellow activists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding &lt;strong&gt;secure communication tools&lt;/strong&gt; that work reliably to share with networks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activism brings constant and sophisticated surveillance, and can lead to restrictions on freedom of movement and association, including loss of employment and &lt;strong&gt;imprisonment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital devices are often confiscated with sensitive data, media, and private personal networks exposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social isolation&lt;/strong&gt; and related depression stem from an inability to communicate privately, and a real fear that friends and family will also be targeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly trained on digital security tools and techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conducts highly sophisticated, thoughtful &lt;strong&gt;analysis of threats and choice of tools&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incredibly savvy on &lt;strong&gt;operational security&lt;/strong&gt; and maintains separate mobile devices for regular activities for secure conversations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I communicate with individuals not already on secure communication channels?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there secure tools that &lt;strong&gt;do not require VPN&lt;/strong&gt; to access?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I &lt;strong&gt;collaborate&lt;/strong&gt; securely with inner circle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I protect my data - on my phone and my computer - against &lt;strong&gt;confiscation&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China: &#34;Z. W.&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/cn-zw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/cn-zw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Z.W. is highly educated, and also respected and accomplished professional with many connections. He is &lt;strong&gt;reflective, respectful, careful, principled&lt;/strong&gt; and is in his late 40s with wife and two children. He is fluent in Mandarin, Cantonese, English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Z. W. recently &lt;strong&gt;posted an article&lt;/strong&gt; perceived as &lt;strong&gt;critical of government authorities&lt;/strong&gt; about a land-grab case occurring on the outskirts of a town in his hometown province. Due to Z.W.’s international connections, previous political statements he has made, his influential position as an academic, and the popularity of the current article he wrote, he was recently &lt;strong&gt;visited by government authorities&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;detained for questioning&lt;/strong&gt;. Several suspicious activities—including &lt;strong&gt;phishing emails&lt;/strong&gt;, and questions from the authorities directed to him about topics not widely known by others—make him certain he is under &lt;strong&gt;active surveillance&lt;/strong&gt;. He is currently investigating moving his family out of the country to ease pressures and is exploring opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Means to &lt;strong&gt;communicate securely&lt;/strong&gt; with family and network both &lt;strong&gt;inside and outside of China&lt;/strong&gt;, both now and if he emigrates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ability to make purchases that are &lt;strong&gt;not traced back&lt;/strong&gt; to him (e.g, new devices, travel, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ability to &lt;strong&gt;lock down his accounts&lt;/strong&gt; to prevent further surveillance, without raising his profile or drawing attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessing and downloading secure tools and applications &lt;strong&gt;could be considered a criminal offence&lt;/strong&gt; due to new NGO and other related laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surveillance of network activity&lt;/strong&gt; and digital devices confiscated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imprisonment, torture&lt;/strong&gt;, and the mental and physical health issues afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trained on digital security tools and techniques; will implement techniques and tools if they work reliably, are usable (i.e., meet the &lt;strong&gt;basic usability standards&lt;/strong&gt; offered by tools such as WeChat, OneDrive, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comfortable with and regularly uses social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regularly accesses databases and conducts fairly complex data analysis in support of academic research work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I maintain social connections with my international network without secure communication methods?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I convince my personal networks to use recommended secure communication tools (e.g., PGP, ChatSecure, Jitsi, etc) when these tools are considered &lt;strong&gt;too onerous&lt;/strong&gt; to setup or so &lt;strong&gt;unreliable&lt;/strong&gt; in functionality and service?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuba: &#34;Yasmany&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/cu_yasmany/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/cu_yasmany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yasmany is a married man in his thirties. He is a &lt;strong&gt;journalist&lt;/strong&gt; based in Cuba and a &lt;strong&gt;vocal advocate&lt;/strong&gt; for Afro-Cuban rights. He uses public transportation to reach his sources and often has to pass through security checkpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses technology to &lt;strong&gt;communicate&lt;/strong&gt; with his colleagues, family, and friends. He also uses his &lt;strong&gt;mobile device&lt;/strong&gt; to record interviews and take pictures. Yasmany has grown accustomed to habitual &lt;strong&gt;harassment&lt;/strong&gt; from the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yasmany needs to &lt;strong&gt;protect&lt;/strong&gt; himself and his stories from the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He needs to &lt;strong&gt;communicate securely&lt;/strong&gt; with his sources and keep his files safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He needs to be able to &lt;strong&gt;record&lt;/strong&gt; interviews on his mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited internet connectivity&lt;/strong&gt; and expensive data plans restrict Yasmany&amp;rsquo;s options when it comes to communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the computers he has access to have government &lt;strong&gt;spyware&lt;/strong&gt; that can track and record both online and offline activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is the subject of &lt;strong&gt;raids&lt;/strong&gt; and sometimes his devices are searched at &lt;strong&gt;security checkpoints&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is &lt;strong&gt;aware&lt;/strong&gt; of the risks that he faces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He makes sure he does not disclose &lt;strong&gt;sensitive information&lt;/strong&gt; in calls and text messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He always &lt;strong&gt;updates&lt;/strong&gt; the software on his devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can the &lt;strong&gt;government&lt;/strong&gt; read my communications?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I &lt;strong&gt;delete&lt;/strong&gt; the content on my phone before handing it over to the &lt;strong&gt;police&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominican Republic: &#34;Jackefine&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/do_jackefine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/do_jackefine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jackefine is a woman in her mid-twenties living in the capital of the Dominican Republic. She is currently attending &lt;strong&gt;university&lt;/strong&gt; and working as an administrative assistant. In her free time, she supports &lt;strong&gt;feminist causes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently she lived with her family, but she now lives with a friend. Her favorite social network is &lt;strong&gt;Facebook,&lt;/strong&gt; which she uses to confidently publish her daily activities. She has a mobile data plan that allows her to use Facebook and &lt;strong&gt;WhatsApp.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to learn how to use &lt;strong&gt;social networks&lt;/strong&gt; and applications to express herself in safe ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to be able to explore her sexuality without facing &lt;strong&gt;harassment online.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicit, sexual content of Jackefine was &lt;strong&gt;published on social media&lt;/strong&gt; and other platforms by her ex-boyfriend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is now receiving a wave of &lt;strong&gt;offensive and sexist messages.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her phone was also &lt;strong&gt;compromised&lt;/strong&gt; and the photos were sent to all of her contacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jackefine owns various devices, including a &lt;strong&gt;mobile phone&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;tablet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has a very strong &lt;strong&gt;support network&lt;/strong&gt; of friends and coworkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is an experienced woman and she &lt;strong&gt;knows her rights.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I need to do to &lt;strong&gt;express myself safely&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there applications that allow you to &lt;strong&gt;protect your identity&lt;/strong&gt; when sending elicit photos?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I prevent the spreading of my photos &lt;strong&gt;without my consent&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia: &#34;Ayu&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/id_ayu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/id_ayu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayu is in her early twenties and identifies as a &lt;strong&gt;Muslim transwoman&lt;/strong&gt;. She grew up in a small village and is part of a conservative family. After facing &lt;strong&gt;violence and harassment&lt;/strong&gt;, she dropped out of high school and fled to Jakarta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She currently works as a &lt;strong&gt;sex worker&lt;/strong&gt; and serves as an advocate for the &lt;strong&gt;LGBTQI community&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses the same &lt;strong&gt;social media networks&lt;/strong&gt; and platforms for her sex work, activism, and to connect with friends and family. So me of these applications are &lt;strong&gt;location-based&lt;/strong&gt; and use her real photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayu wants to continue her work and activism without &lt;strong&gt;risking her life&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;endangering&lt;/strong&gt; the people around her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She needs to develop &lt;strong&gt;cost-effective&lt;/strong&gt; strategies to keep her work and activism separate from her personal life and to ensure that her &lt;strong&gt;information is secure&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She faces daily &lt;strong&gt;online harassment&lt;/strong&gt; and attacks based on her identity as a transwoman, a sex worker, and an activist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People, including the government and religious conservatives, can &lt;strong&gt;collect information&lt;/strong&gt; about Ayu from her online accounts and use it to persecute and attack her both online and physically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She invites clients to her home which poses a &lt;strong&gt;physical danger&lt;/strong&gt; to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayu is &lt;strong&gt;tech savvy&lt;/strong&gt; in terms of using and navigating applications on her Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She works independently and has the power to choose her clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is very committed to activism and is a &lt;strong&gt;strong voice&lt;/strong&gt; within the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I use &lt;strong&gt;social media&lt;/strong&gt; for my work, my activism, and personal life securely?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I respond to &lt;strong&gt;online attacks&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I separate my personal and professional lives?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia: &#34;Husna&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/id_husna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/id_husna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husna is an Indonesian woman in her mid twenties. She is an advocate for both &lt;strong&gt;freedom of expression&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;religious freedom&lt;/strong&gt;. For many years, she has worked on issues related to peace building, deradicalization, and journalism that supports the peace process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses social media to &lt;strong&gt;spread messages and information&lt;/strong&gt; to the general public. She also uses social media to &lt;strong&gt;coordinate activities&lt;/strong&gt; for different minority rights groups. The various groups are using Facebook, including Facebook Messenger, to coordinate their activities. The groups use Twitter to &lt;strong&gt;gain more public interest and support&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husna hopes for a better society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She hopes that Indonesia will protect &lt;strong&gt;pluralism&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to make sure that the government does not pass &lt;strong&gt;discriminatory policies&lt;/strong&gt; against minority religions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are often government agents or intelligence officers &lt;strong&gt;physically present&lt;/strong&gt; at the events Husna helps coordinate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is at risk of &lt;strong&gt;attacks&lt;/strong&gt; from paramilitary groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State actors use &lt;strong&gt;surveillance&lt;/strong&gt; to track Husna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husna is a very brave advocate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She believes strongly in the values of pluralism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She supports and has access to a &lt;strong&gt;large network&lt;/strong&gt; of people that have different beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I keep myself &lt;strong&gt;safe&lt;/strong&gt; while using Facebook and other &lt;strong&gt;social media&lt;/strong&gt; sites?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I keep myself safe while the &lt;strong&gt;government is monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What type of chat applications or &lt;strong&gt;communication channels&lt;/strong&gt; are safe for us to use?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan: &#34;Ahmed&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/jo_ahmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/jo_ahmed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahmed is a &lt;strong&gt;student&lt;/strong&gt; at a Jordanian university. He is concerned about the state of affairs in his country and he wants to &lt;strong&gt;raise awareness&lt;/strong&gt; about what is happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahmed always tries to express his concerns &lt;strong&gt;securely and anonymously&lt;/strong&gt;, usually relying on social media networks to do so. He has not yet faced any prosecution or retaliation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wants to oe able to express himself &lt;strong&gt;freely and securely&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wants to communicate securely using WhatsApp and &lt;strong&gt;anonymously&lt;/strong&gt; using faoebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He fears that being vocal about his opinions online will endanger his safety and might lead to &lt;strong&gt;arrest&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He fears that expressing opimions that are different will &lt;strong&gt;alienate&lt;/strong&gt; him in his society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is worried he may be &lt;strong&gt;surveilled&lt;/strong&gt; or his devices may be &lt;strong&gt;confiscated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahmed owns a &lt;strong&gt;smart phone&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is familiar with using &lt;strong&gt;social media networks&lt;/strong&gt; for communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He can write and understand some &lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I be &lt;strong&gt;anonymous&lt;/strong&gt; on facebook?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I protect myself from &lt;strong&gt;surveillance&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I make sure messages to my friends are only read by the &lt;strong&gt;intended recipient&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kenya: &#34;Alexandria Christian&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ky_alexandria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ky_alexandria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexandria is based in Nairobi, Kenya. She is married and in her late twenties with a young child. She is a &lt;strong&gt;lawyer&lt;/strong&gt; by profession, but is also a &lt;strong&gt;champion of women&amp;rsquo;s rights&lt;/strong&gt;. She has been very vocal about FGM and has received some backlash for her activism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of her anti-FGM work, Alexandria uses an application that enables volunteers to rescue young girls and relocate them. Alexandria is responsible for &lt;strong&gt;coordinating the volunteers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to be able to &lt;strong&gt;track&lt;/strong&gt; the movement to my volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need an application which has an &lt;strong&gt;emergency button&lt;/strong&gt; for when there is no time to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexandria&amp;rsquo;s child has been downloading apps on her phone without her knowledge. The downloaded software included &lt;strong&gt;malware,&lt;/strong&gt; which &lt;strong&gt;compromised sensitive information&lt;/strong&gt; stored on her device. The malware is also capable of downloading and installing other apps and can do so without detection. Alexandria does not know how much information has been &lt;strong&gt;leaked&lt;/strong&gt; so far, but the volunteers are vulnerable to attacks since their identities have been revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexandria makes sure that her software is always updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also makes sure that all volunteer files are &lt;strong&gt;encrypted&lt;/strong&gt; and is able to use the application to spread her message and get more people involved in anti-FGM efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I still &lt;strong&gt;safely&lt;/strong&gt; use my phone after deleting all the apps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I do to &lt;strong&gt;avoid&lt;/strong&gt; such incidents in the future?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kenya: &#34;Mary&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ky_mary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ky_mary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary is a &lt;strong&gt;digital security trainer, gender policy expert, and a research consultant&lt;/strong&gt; with many years of experience conducting research for different organizations. She also trains activists and local communities on skills for adopting strategic non-violence and movement building to affect social change. She works as an &lt;strong&gt;IT assistant&lt;/strong&gt; for an organization that promotes environmental rights. Recently, the organization was hit by &lt;strong&gt;ransomware&lt;/strong&gt; and they lost a lot of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses a &lt;strong&gt;laptop for work and trainings&lt;/strong&gt; and uses &lt;strong&gt;bitlocker and Veracrypt&lt;/strong&gt; to encrypt files and drives. She makes sure to use secure plug-ins in browser to enhance security. She also uses a cellphone daily and occasionally uses &lt;strong&gt;social media.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary wants to learn more about ethical hacking in order to help human rights defenders better protect their systems. Since her organization was recently attacked by ransomware, she wants to make sure she has the best antivirus possible to &lt;strong&gt;protect their network and data.&lt;/strong&gt; She would like to &lt;strong&gt;strengthen her organization&amp;rsquo;s IT policies,&lt;/strong&gt; including back up procedures, to prevent this from happening again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed Denial of Service (DDOS)&lt;/strong&gt; attacks have been happening to other Human Rights Organizations in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spam and phishing&lt;/strong&gt; emails and SMS messages are often received by members of her organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Physical security&lt;/strong&gt; is a concern, as office and home break ins are common in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary is able to train others in digital security, including those in her organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses &lt;strong&gt;file encryption and a password manager&lt;/strong&gt; to store strong passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has a &lt;strong&gt;strong technical background,&lt;/strong&gt; and can install and configure different operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can &lt;strong&gt;internet of things&lt;/strong&gt; devices be secured?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I stop or minimize spam emails in my gmail inbox?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kenya: Denis</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ky_denis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ky_denis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denis is an &lt;strong&gt;IT Officer and project manager&lt;/strong&gt; in his early 30s. He does work for an organization that works towards the realization of environmental and human rights for the economically marginalized communities around extractive industries and toxic sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denis is married and has one daughter. In his free time, he works on &lt;strong&gt;designing a tool&lt;/strong&gt; that his community can use to report cases on industries that toxify the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses his &lt;strong&gt;computer and cell phone&lt;/strong&gt; daily, and uses &lt;strong&gt;KeePassXC&lt;/strong&gt; to manage his passwords and &lt;strong&gt;Tresorit&lt;/strong&gt; to back up the organization&amp;rsquo;s data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denis wants to become a &lt;strong&gt;computer and data security expert&lt;/strong&gt; in order to help his community learn how to store their data and keep their computers safe. With his knowledge in programming, he wants to &lt;strong&gt;develop a tool&lt;/strong&gt; that can track manufacturing industries in his country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His other goal is to have a &lt;strong&gt;secure communication channel&lt;/strong&gt; for the organization that can be used for reporting cases and complaints from the community to the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surveillance&lt;/strong&gt; of phone calls and the hacking of organization&amp;rsquo;s online accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His &lt;strong&gt;physical security&lt;/strong&gt; is at risk, as targeted office break-ins are common in his city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His &lt;strong&gt;laptop and phone may be stolen&lt;/strong&gt; during a break-in or robbery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He can &lt;strong&gt;train others&lt;/strong&gt; to create strong passwords and enable two-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is able to &lt;strong&gt;identify a computer threat&lt;/strong&gt; and clean it. He can use any computer programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is known as a &lt;strong&gt;trusted technical expert&lt;/strong&gt; in his community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I &lt;strong&gt;encrypt my phone calls&lt;/strong&gt; free of cost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I be anonymous online?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the best tool to &lt;strong&gt;recover deleted data?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kenya: Peter</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ky_peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ky_peter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter is a health worker in his community and also works for an &lt;strong&gt;environmental and human rights advocacy&lt;/strong&gt; organization based in Mombasa, Kenya as a researcher. His day to day activities include researching the possible dangers that industrial waste can cause to humans and the environment. He lives with his wife, two sons, and one daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter uses a &lt;strong&gt;laptop for work&lt;/strong&gt; daily, and a cellphone to communicate with colleagues as well as his family. He uses &lt;strong&gt;dropbox&lt;/strong&gt; to store findings from the field, and uses &lt;strong&gt;Skype&lt;/strong&gt; often to communicate with colleagues and partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter&amp;rsquo;s biggest concern is the &lt;strong&gt;privacy&lt;/strong&gt; of his patients. He wants to make sure that he is using a &lt;strong&gt;secure application&lt;/strong&gt; that can store the details of patients securely, in order to &lt;strong&gt;protect their privacy.&lt;/strong&gt; He would also like to have an application that can monitor the supply of government drugs in hospitals to ensure that they are adequately stocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an environmentalist, he is at risk of being &lt;strong&gt;targeted and cyber-bullied&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If his &lt;strong&gt;devices are stolen,&lt;/strong&gt; all of his research data will be at risk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a healthcare professional, he is at risk of &lt;strong&gt;patients&#39; data leaking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is aware of the risks that he faces if he does not take steps to protect his accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses &lt;strong&gt;2fa on Facebook and Gmail&lt;/strong&gt; accounts to keep them secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is a &lt;strong&gt;great communicator,&lt;/strong&gt; and can make presentations for those in his community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the &lt;strong&gt;best tool to encrypt my data&lt;/strong&gt; on my computer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I protect the details of patients from being stolen and leaked?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I &lt;strong&gt;bypass blocked content&lt;/strong&gt; on the internet?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lebanon: &#34;Lara&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/lb_lara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/lb_lara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lara is a Lebanese woman in her late twenties. She works as a &lt;strong&gt;journalist&lt;/strong&gt; and is also a &lt;strong&gt;well-informed activist&lt;/strong&gt;. She stays up-to-date on all current events and the latest news updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of her activism, she has been &lt;strong&gt;targeted&lt;/strong&gt; by the government and other entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses &lt;strong&gt;chat applications&lt;/strong&gt; like WhatsApp to communicate with her colleagues and connect with sources for her reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She needs to &lt;strong&gt;communicate securely&lt;/strong&gt; with her contacts and sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to &lt;strong&gt;better understand&lt;/strong&gt; how to safely use the applications she is already using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has previously been the target of &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;man in the middle&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She could be &lt;strong&gt;imprisoned&lt;/strong&gt; as a result of defamation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She often receives &lt;strong&gt;phishing&lt;/strong&gt; links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She believes that she has &lt;strong&gt;nothing to hide&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She writes bold articles that &lt;strong&gt;educate&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;inspire others&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She knows that unencrypted apps are the most &lt;strong&gt;vulnerable&lt;/strong&gt; in terms of security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it &lt;strong&gt;safe&lt;/strong&gt; to use WhatsApp?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there &lt;strong&gt;another application&lt;/strong&gt; that I should be using for secure communication?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I encourage other people to use &lt;strong&gt;secure applications&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexico: &#34;Maria&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/mx-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/mx-m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maria is in her mid 30’s and is passionate in &lt;strong&gt;advocating for the rights of people with disabilities&lt;/strong&gt; in Mexico. She has been &lt;strong&gt;blind since she was very young&lt;/strong&gt; and faces a slew of accessibility challenges when using technology in her work and personal life. She must use a &lt;strong&gt;screen reader&lt;/strong&gt; to navigate her laptop and mobile devices, using a free and open-source version for Windows called, NVDA, and the built-in reader for iPhone, called, VoiceOver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maria and her colleagues face &lt;strong&gt;unique privacy and security concerns&lt;/strong&gt; both as activists and as persons who are blind because their &lt;strong&gt;inability to autonomously handle their most sensitive information&lt;/strong&gt; makes it impossible to handle such information securely. They are also more susceptible to other forms of digital attacks, as &lt;strong&gt;software is not consistently accessible&lt;/strong&gt; and navigable –- making it hard to pinpoint or identify abnormal activity sometimes on their devices (e.g. pop-ups, advertisements vs malware and viruses).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advance accessibility for all persons with disabilities through &lt;strong&gt;public advocacy&lt;/strong&gt; and policy changes in both the public and private sectors and through the &lt;strong&gt;promotion of accessibility standards&lt;/strong&gt; and testing products using the free and open-source screen reader, NVDA and VoiceOver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop a strategy and build the capacity of users with disabilities to &lt;strong&gt;prevent misuse of their data&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;personal rights.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From digital security tools to normal tasks like checking bank statements, online shopping, or captchas; &lt;strong&gt;tools that are inaccessible are not usable.&lt;/strong&gt; This requires Maria to rely on and &lt;strong&gt;share private information&lt;/strong&gt; with family and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loss of information, fraudulent sites, malware, and webcam activation can happen without accessible alerts informing the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people with disabilities cannot complete tasks online, they must go to a location in-person, which can lead to physical threats due to infrastructure problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very &lt;strong&gt;comfortable with technology&lt;/strong&gt; and developing ways to &lt;strong&gt;work around accessibility problems&lt;/strong&gt; to accomplish tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Committed to supporting the rights of persons with disabilities and increasing awareness of these accessibility issues in technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in fostering a community of people with disabilities with whom to share experiences and ideas about improvements that can be made to &lt;strong&gt;improve technologies and make them accessible.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I determine which websites and tools are accessible and secure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a security tool is not accessible, what are my best alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who can I contact about making this tool more accessible or if it is not working properly with NVDA or VoiceOver?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nepal: &#34;Chumi&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/np_chumi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/np_chumi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chumi is a &lt;strong&gt;lesbian&lt;/strong&gt; woman in her mid thirties. She grew up in a small town in Nepal, but now lives in the capital and works at an organization focused on advancing the &lt;strong&gt;rights of LGBT people&lt;/strong&gt;. Her organization advocates for gender equality and LGBT inclusive environments around the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses Facebook, WhatsApp, and email to &lt;strong&gt;communicate&lt;/strong&gt; with community members, &lt;strong&gt;collect stories&lt;/strong&gt; from the community, provide real-time &lt;strong&gt;counseling&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;share legal updates&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants LGBTI community members to be able to live in society with &lt;strong&gt;dignity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to make others &lt;strong&gt;aware&lt;/strong&gt; of laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to &lt;strong&gt;protect&lt;/strong&gt; herself, the people she works with, and her information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has received &lt;strong&gt;death threats&lt;/strong&gt; due to her advocacy for the LGBTI community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her &lt;strong&gt;personal information&lt;/strong&gt; is on the internet and is published frequently by the media, which means other people have access to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is &lt;strong&gt;harassed&lt;/strong&gt; online because of her LGBTI identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chumi has strong &lt;strong&gt;advocating power&lt;/strong&gt; and a lot of community members who support her activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is very &lt;strong&gt;active online&lt;/strong&gt; and the media looks to her as a &lt;strong&gt;trusted source of information&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has a lot of experience using technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can people &lt;strong&gt;safely tell their stories&lt;/strong&gt; on social media? Do people have to make anonymous accounts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the safest way to &lt;strong&gt;video conference&lt;/strong&gt; with community members?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which tools are &lt;strong&gt;secure&lt;/strong&gt;? Which should I &lt;strong&gt;recommend&lt;/strong&gt; for community members?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nepal: &#34;Maya&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/np_maya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/np_maya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maya is a Nepalese woman in her early thirties. She is an &lt;strong&gt;information advocate&lt;/strong&gt;, an avid researcher, and is very active on Twitter and Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is a well-known journalist in Nepal with many Twitter and other &lt;strong&gt;social media&lt;/strong&gt; followers. She primarily writes about &lt;strong&gt;politics&lt;/strong&gt;, sharing news and tweets related to political events or incidents happening in the country. Often times, she investigates and reports on her stories by physically going to the location of the incident or where the event is taking place, putting her at risk of &lt;strong&gt;physical harm&lt;/strong&gt;. When she publishes her stories, many times they are seen as &lt;strong&gt;sensitive&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;controversial&lt;/strong&gt; in nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maya believes in the &lt;strong&gt;right to information&lt;/strong&gt; and is therefore committed to sharing sensitive information with the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As she has already been a victim of violence, she prioritizes the &lt;strong&gt;safety&lt;/strong&gt; of herself as well as those she works with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She often shares &lt;strong&gt;sensitive information&lt;/strong&gt; about important and powerful figures in Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She covers &lt;strong&gt;controversial issues&lt;/strong&gt; from corruption to migration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She takes the same route every day. She is concerned that she will be &lt;strong&gt;stalked or harassed&lt;/strong&gt; on her commute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her devices could be &lt;strong&gt;confiscated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maya has strong research skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is known by many as a pioneer of the right to information and is regarded as one of the most &lt;strong&gt;credible sources&lt;/strong&gt; in Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses her Android phone for public uses and her iPhone for personal uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I &lt;strong&gt;protect my devices&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I have &lt;strong&gt;free mobility&lt;/strong&gt; despite being very active on social media?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I &lt;strong&gt;protect information&lt;/strong&gt; about myself and my friends?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nicaragua: &#34;Esteban Ramirez&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ni_esteban/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ni_esteban/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esteban is a &lt;strong&gt;journalist&lt;/strong&gt; in his mid-twenties. He works at a small newspaper in Managua, Nicaragua. He reports on thematic issues, often using &lt;strong&gt;public transportation&lt;/strong&gt; to meet with sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a journalist, he relies on technology to &lt;strong&gt;communicate&lt;/strong&gt; with his sources. He wants to improve his digital security to ensure that he is not endangering himself or those he interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esteban needs a &lt;strong&gt;secure chat&lt;/strong&gt; platform to use when communicating with his sources, many of whom are people at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wants to be sure that his &lt;strong&gt;data and conversations&lt;/strong&gt; are not revealed to third parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esteban&amp;rsquo;s sources have &lt;strong&gt;limited access&lt;/strong&gt; to the internet and little knowledge about safe applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esteban and his sources use devices with &lt;strong&gt;low storage&lt;/strong&gt; capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esteban has &lt;strong&gt;connections&lt;/strong&gt; within the technological community, including with developers and bloggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is constantly &lt;strong&gt;up-to-date&lt;/strong&gt; with new technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What applications will allow me to &lt;strong&gt;securely communicate&lt;/strong&gt; with my sources?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there tools that are &lt;strong&gt;easy to use&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russia: &#34;Marina&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ru_marina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ru_marina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marina is in her mid-thirties and works as an activist, blogger, and local community organizer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses different technologies to post about local issues, to &lt;strong&gt;communicate&lt;/strong&gt; with fellow activists, and to &lt;strong&gt;organize protests&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She often takes photos to post on social media and has organized &lt;strong&gt;petitions&lt;/strong&gt; that are sent to local administrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants her voice to be heard by the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also wants to use tools that are &lt;strong&gt;easily accessible&lt;/strong&gt; for other activists and community members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local authorities launch &lt;strong&gt;DDoS attacks&lt;/strong&gt; and employ trolls and hackers against her Facebook account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police can &lt;strong&gt;arrest&lt;/strong&gt; Marina and &lt;strong&gt;confiscate&lt;/strong&gt; her phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her followers and supporters could face &lt;strong&gt;persecution&lt;/strong&gt; if exposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is knowledgeable about &lt;strong&gt;social networks&lt;/strong&gt; and social applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is &lt;strong&gt;internet savvy&lt;/strong&gt; and is fluent in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I prevent the identities of supporters from being &lt;strong&gt;leaked&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I protect my Facebook, email, and IM from hackers and prevent them from being &lt;strong&gt;blocked&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russia: &#34;Sasha&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ru_sasha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ru_sasha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sasha is in his early thirties and works as a systems administrator at a civil society organization. He is very &lt;strong&gt;skeptical&lt;/strong&gt; and has a &lt;strong&gt;critical approach&lt;/strong&gt; to everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He relies on technology to keep his organization &lt;strong&gt;safe&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After work, he sometimes attends concerts, plays computer games, or hangs out with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though he would never show it, he is an activist and he believes it is his duty to keep the organization &lt;strong&gt;safe&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He believes that everything should be very well &lt;strong&gt;organized&lt;/strong&gt; and work correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His organization works on politically sensitive issues li1ke &lt;strong&gt;hacking, protests, eavesdropping, and provocations&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro-government youth movements are regularly &lt;strong&gt;verbally attacking&lt;/strong&gt; his colleagues and sometimes unexpected office visits from pro-government stations occur. Sasha&amp;rsquo;s colleagues are not tech-savvy and they often make a lot of &lt;strong&gt;critical digital security mistakes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is skilled with technology and views everything through a critical lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has access to his entire organization&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;network&lt;/strong&gt;, which he set up by himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I &lt;strong&gt;teach&lt;/strong&gt; all of my organization&amp;rsquo;s employees better digital security practices (use of &lt;strong&gt;strong passwords&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2-factor authentication&lt;/strong&gt;, etc.)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I be sure that people will &lt;strong&gt;use&lt;/strong&gt; the tools I train them on?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: &#34;Fatima&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/sd_fatima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/sd_fatima/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatima is in her late twenties and is an &lt;strong&gt;advocate for women&amp;rsquo;s rights&lt;/strong&gt; in Sudan. She works with students from the local university and other local women, advising them on funding opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She relies on her phone and computer to &lt;strong&gt;stay connected&lt;/strong&gt; with the community and to &lt;strong&gt;store important data&lt;/strong&gt;. She also uses Skype to communicate with women remotely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to make FGM and child marriage illegal in Sudan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to &lt;strong&gt;raise awareness&lt;/strong&gt; about gender-based violence and domestic violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to help women in her country &lt;strong&gt;raise their voices&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on these issues makes her a target of phone tapping, email hacking, and home raids. If targeted, her &lt;strong&gt;data could be Lost or compromised&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is also at risk of &lt;strong&gt;verbal and physical abuse or arrest&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatima has knowledge of the community and has many &lt;strong&gt;strong relationships&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is also &lt;strong&gt;familiar with technology&lt;/strong&gt; and she is comfortable using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I do to make sure I do not &lt;strong&gt;lose my data&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If needed, what ways can I &lt;strong&gt;hide sensitive information&lt;/strong&gt; on my laptop?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I make sure everyone is &lt;strong&gt;safe&lt;/strong&gt; when they contact me?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syria: &#34;Majeed&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/sy_majeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/sy_majeed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Majeed is a civil society activist who works with a &lt;strong&gt;large network&lt;/strong&gt; of Syrian activists involved in efforts to advocate for democracy. He is well respected within this community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He needs to use a plethora of &lt;strong&gt;communication applications&lt;/strong&gt; to coorainate with activists and influencers. Communication is critical to their cause and success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Majeed is most concerned that he will become a &lt;strong&gt;target&lt;/strong&gt; of the Syrian government and their allies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Majeed needs to maintain contact with many activists, but wants to &lt;strong&gt;reduce the number of applications&lt;/strong&gt; he uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also needs to reduce the &lt;strong&gt;risks&lt;/strong&gt; he faces and exposes others to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is afraid that personal information or incriminating data about him or his network will be &lt;strong&gt;exposed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is worried about &lt;strong&gt;losing contact&lt;/strong&gt; with people due to application deprecation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also possible that Majeed&amp;rsquo;s devices could be &lt;strong&gt;lost or confiscated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Majeed is computer and mobile literate and is also aware of &lt;strong&gt;digital threats&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is well respected and is considered a &lt;strong&gt;leader&lt;/strong&gt; in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is not dependent on the &lt;strong&gt;government internet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many &lt;strong&gt;communication applications&lt;/strong&gt; out there. How do I know which is the best?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more applications I use, the more I am &lt;strong&gt;exposed to risk&lt;/strong&gt; if one is compromised. How can I mitigate that?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syria: &#34;Marwa&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/sy_m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/sy_m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marwa is a 20-year-old journalist who grew up in Syria, later moving to a neighboring country due to increased violence in her region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience has made her &lt;strong&gt;resilient and quick to adapt&lt;/strong&gt;. Although she has fled the physical danger of conflict in Syria, she now faces new threats because of her profession, from &lt;strong&gt;targeted surveillance&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;advanced malware&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as an increasing number of border skirmishes and &lt;strong&gt;assassination attempts&lt;/strong&gt; on journalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses a wide-range of applications, but most notably Facebook, to share her stories with a broader audience inside and outside of Syria. She is often willing to take risks and has been &lt;strong&gt;desensitized&lt;/strong&gt; to a point where securing her data is not a high priority most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She needs to &lt;strong&gt;communicate and share&lt;/strong&gt; what is happening in Syria as efficiently as she can, sometimes as a form of criticism or dissent, but mostly to &lt;strong&gt;disseminate information&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;raise awareness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also requires regular communication with her &lt;strong&gt;vast network&lt;/strong&gt; of friends and followers (some of whom she does not necessarily know personally).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phishing attacks&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;malware&lt;/strong&gt; exposure to her devices both from &lt;strong&gt;state and non-state actors&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surveillance&lt;/strong&gt; of her communication by both the hostcountry and Syria and &lt;strong&gt;misinformation&lt;/strong&gt; about their capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imprisonment&lt;/strong&gt; and unintentionally putting others at risk through their connection with her, particularly family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revealing networks due to &lt;strong&gt;device confiscation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fearless journalist&lt;/strong&gt; with a strong voice and a powerful message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very &lt;strong&gt;adaptable&lt;/strong&gt; to a range of circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Committed to returning home and supporting her people in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I trust that what you’re telling me is true?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I &lt;strong&gt;secure my social networks&lt;/strong&gt;? And how can communicate with my network if they don’t use a particular tool?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting my message out is more important than security. What are some ways I can &lt;strong&gt;balance&lt;/strong&gt; this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I protect myself and my friends?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uganda: &#34;Jomeo Richard&#34;&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ug_jomeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ug_jomeo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jomeo is in his late twenties and based in Uganda. He works with &lt;strong&gt;anti-corruption&lt;/strong&gt; groups to create &lt;strong&gt;public awareness&lt;/strong&gt; about the ongoing and severe violations and abuses of human rights by both public and private individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work involves &lt;strong&gt;monitoring and documenting human rights violations&lt;/strong&gt; and corruption through digital media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is not very experienced in the use of technology to collect sensitive information, but he has used Signal and PGP to communicate securely with his contacts. The group he works with has some technical capacity and experience with digital security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jomeo wants to continue to use the internet as a primary medium to expose corruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He needs to &lt;strong&gt;build his capacity&lt;/strong&gt; to promote governance, human rights, accountability, and transparency through social media and avid blogging. He also needs to maintain a &lt;strong&gt;secure&lt;/strong&gt; environment to protect his work and his sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is the target of &lt;strong&gt;intimidation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;harrassment&lt;/strong&gt; by police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office and home &lt;strong&gt;raids&lt;/strong&gt; lead to the &lt;strong&gt;confiscation&lt;/strong&gt; of phones, laptops, flash disks, modems, and soft and hard copies of documents by security operatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surveillance&lt;/strong&gt; is a concern, as phones have been tapped. Other concerns include &lt;strong&gt;imprisonment&lt;/strong&gt; and degradation of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jomeo has previously attended &lt;strong&gt;security trainings&lt;/strong&gt;. He learned how to maintain strong passwords, enable 2-step verification, and how to securely communicate via encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also backs up confidential documents to ensure &lt;strong&gt;safe storage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His groups are helping keep him up-to-date with digital security measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can happen to me if I am &lt;strong&gt;arrested&lt;/strong&gt; without my colleagues knowledge?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I &lt;strong&gt;communicate&lt;/strong&gt; with my contacts about the arrest?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uganda: &#34;Paul Mukasa&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ug-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ug-pm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul is LGBTI in Uganda, where it is &lt;strong&gt;illegal&lt;/strong&gt; and not socially accepted. He faces both &lt;strong&gt;ostracism and physical risk.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul and his organization work with politicians and civil society leaders to improve the acceptance of LGBTI issues across Uganda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul is currently leading an internal project at his organization to improve their &lt;strong&gt;security practices&lt;/strong&gt; - both at the organization and at many staff members&#39; homes, they have biometric alarm systems installed after a series of break-ins and office raids where laptops were stolen. Other practices Paul is working to address are sharing laptops in the office and discouraging using cybercafes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul is between 29 and 35. He is single and lives alone, as his close family have emigrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping himself and his colleagues safe &amp;ndash; both at their office and their homes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintaining ability to &lt;strong&gt;advocate&lt;/strong&gt; for social change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ability to have an active social and family life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strong social norms against LGBTI - including everyday people, religious fundamentalists, police with prejudices, and &lt;strong&gt;illegality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office and home &lt;strong&gt;raids and robberies;&lt;/strong&gt; including the seizure of laptops. Stolen information can be sold to the media, which &amp;ldquo;out&amp;rdquo; activists publicly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intense government &lt;strong&gt;surveillance&lt;/strong&gt; of activist and NGO activity using powerful tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul has readily adopted many digital security practices - enabling &lt;strong&gt;two factor authentication&lt;/strong&gt; for accounts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul has developed complex &lt;strong&gt;operational security&lt;/strong&gt; practices, such as having personal protocols of how to engage with new contacts in public spaces instead of at the office, to reduce associational risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After recent office raids, Paul and other staff have moved to saving documents in cloud storage and not on laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I &lt;strong&gt;protect information&lt;/strong&gt; against my devices being confiscated?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I encourage colleagues, partners, and funders to adopt better security practices?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: &#34;Anna&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ua_anna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ua_anna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna is a middle-aged woman, working for an &lt;strong&gt;anti-corruption&lt;/strong&gt; non-governmental organization in Ukraine. She leads many cases against high-profile corruption within the Ukrainian government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She &lt;strong&gt;stores important documents&lt;/strong&gt; on her Laptop. She uses &lt;strong&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/strong&gt; to communicate with her team and family. She often needs to &lt;strong&gt;print documents&lt;/strong&gt; in order to file legal requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to win her cases against &lt;strong&gt;corrupted officials&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to keep herself and her team merrnbers &lt;strong&gt;safe&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;state-Level actors&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her phone was &lt;strong&gt;stolen&lt;/strong&gt; and then returned by a ranaom person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her team conversations on WhatsApp have been repeatedly &lt;strong&gt;leaked&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be some documents on her device that could potentially &lt;strong&gt;incriminate&lt;/strong&gt; her and other innocent people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna uses &lt;strong&gt;full-disk encryption&lt;/strong&gt; and all of her devices are &lt;strong&gt;password protected&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses WhatsApp for all important conversations and has &lt;strong&gt;2-factor authentication&lt;/strong&gt; enabled on all important accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can someone &lt;strong&gt;break into my device&lt;/strong&gt; if it is locked?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was told that WhatsApp is safe, so how can our information be &lt;strong&gt;repeatedly leaked&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: &#34;Maksym&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ua-maksym/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ua-maksym/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maksym is in his late twenties and works as a history teacher in Ukraine. During his free time, &lt;strong&gt;he works as an admin and editor for a social media page&lt;/strong&gt; of a local activist group. The group fights against city gentrification and the destruction of local parks for residential development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses his Laptop to access his personal pages and advocacy groups on &lt;strong&gt;Facebook&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;VKontakte&lt;/strong&gt;. He uses &lt;strong&gt;Telegram&lt;/strong&gt; to communicate with his fellow activists and ephemeral online notepads (i.e. privnote.com) for sensitive communication. He uses different &lt;strong&gt;VPN clients&lt;/strong&gt; to access VKontakte pages that are blocked in Ukraine due to sanctions on Russia, as a large part of his audience still uses the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wants to keep his true identity secret in order to &lt;strong&gt;protect his job&lt;/strong&gt; as a teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He needs to me sure that his Facebook pages are &lt;strong&gt;secure&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;available&lt;/strong&gt; at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wants to &lt;strong&gt;engage the local community&lt;/strong&gt; in the struggLe against gentrification and corruption of city officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several members of his group have been temporarily &lt;strong&gt;arrested&lt;/strong&gt; in the past on fake charges and their devices were &lt;strong&gt;confiscated&lt;/strong&gt;. Their &lt;strong&gt;social media pages were deleted&lt;/strong&gt; after devices were confiscated by authorities. This caused them to lose a large portion of their audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is afraid that his &lt;strong&gt;identity will be revealed&lt;/strong&gt; by law enforcement or corrupt officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maksym&amp;rsquo;s devices are &lt;strong&gt;password protected&lt;/strong&gt; and he has &lt;strong&gt;2-factor authentication&lt;/strong&gt; enabled on all important accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses Telegram for most conversations and privnote.com for sensitive communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also uses &lt;strong&gt;aliases&lt;/strong&gt; on all his personal social media accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can someone &lt;strong&gt;track me&lt;/strong&gt; using my phone number (since you do not need to register a SIM card with a specific name in Ukraine yet)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I do to &lt;strong&gt;protect our social media pages&lt;/strong&gt; from being deleted if my devices were to be seized?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: &#34;Masha&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ua-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ua-m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Masha is based in Kyiv, and works for an NGO tracking &lt;strong&gt;human rights violations&lt;/strong&gt; ocurring in the contested Donetsk region of Eastern Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She coordinates monitoring missions of volunteers who travel into Donetsk to interview and document violations using their &lt;strong&gt;cell phones&lt;/strong&gt;, and return to &lt;strong&gt;share and organize the information&lt;/strong&gt;. Her responsibility is to plan the missions and logistics, select and send volunteers to the area, and &lt;strong&gt;monitor their work and safety&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Masha is an &lt;strong&gt;experienced user&lt;/strong&gt; of digital security tools, including &lt;strong&gt;encrypted email&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;password managers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the volunteer network she works with has high turn-over, and different skill levels and understanding of digital security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She needs the ability to &lt;strong&gt;track the volunteers&#39; movement&lt;/strong&gt; in the area in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fast, safe tool to synchronize data from volunteer smartphones, so the data does not get &lt;strong&gt;confiscated and lost&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volunteers need an &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;SOS&amp;rdquo; button&lt;/strong&gt; for when there is no time to communicate, but need to send an alert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation the volunteers gather is &lt;strong&gt;very sensitive&lt;/strong&gt; to both sides of the conflict; neither side wants these facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To preserve the information and keep the volunteers safe, they need to &lt;strong&gt;remove the data from the mobile phone&lt;/strong&gt; as fast as possible, as the &lt;strong&gt;devices may be seized&lt;/strong&gt; at any moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation in Donetsk is &lt;strong&gt;unpredictable&lt;/strong&gt;, and communications channels may go down without warning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced user who has been trained in and adopted digital security methods. She has &lt;strong&gt;different passwords&lt;/strong&gt; for different services, and &lt;strong&gt;updates her software&lt;/strong&gt; regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She uses &lt;strong&gt;file encryption&lt;/strong&gt; for files on her laptop, and uses gmail with &lt;strong&gt;two-factor authentication&lt;/strong&gt; for her email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The volunteers have &lt;strong&gt;widely different levels&lt;/strong&gt; of tech skills and need tools which are &lt;strong&gt;fast to learn&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;easy to use&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens to the information if the &lt;strong&gt;mobile phone is confiscated&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can it work if &lt;strong&gt;communications are blocked&lt;/strong&gt; or completely cut off?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I safely &lt;strong&gt;track the location&lt;/strong&gt; of the volunteers without revealing that information to anyone else?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: &#34;Oleksandr&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ua_oleksandr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ua_oleksandr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oleksandr is in his mid-thirties and works as a &lt;strong&gt;television journalist&lt;/strong&gt;. He covers stories in the combat areas of Eastern Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses his mobile phone and iPad for &lt;strong&gt;communicating with colleagues&lt;/strong&gt;, sources, and others. He also &lt;strong&gt;takes photos&lt;/strong&gt; for Facebook stories on his mobile phone and iPad and &lt;strong&gt;stores sensitive files&lt;/strong&gt; on his laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wants to be sure that his communication with sources will be &lt;strong&gt;private&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He needs to make sure that soldiers will not be able to access his &lt;strong&gt;sensitive files&lt;/strong&gt; (photos, documents, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has to leave his laptop in hotels and connect to &lt;strong&gt;public WiFi&lt;/strong&gt; near combat areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His laptop can be &lt;strong&gt;searched&lt;/strong&gt; at the border or check-point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His Google and Facebook accounts could be targets of &lt;strong&gt;phishing attempts&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oleksandr has &lt;strong&gt;encrypted&lt;/strong&gt; his iPhone, iPad, and MacBook already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has also attended a one-day &lt;strong&gt;digital security training&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I &lt;strong&gt;secure communications&lt;/strong&gt; via Gmail, Facebook, and Viber?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can the military get files from my laptop &lt;strong&gt;without my password&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: &#34;Oleksandr&#34;</title>
      <link>https://usable.tools/personas/ua_oleksandr2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 23:15:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usable.tools/personas/ua_oleksandr2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oleksandr is in his forties and works as both a lawyer and human rights defender. He is currently working on &lt;strong&gt;legal cases of human rights violations&lt;/strong&gt;, which involves preparing documents for international courts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He uses &lt;strong&gt;2-factor authentication&lt;/strong&gt; with Gmail, Google Drive, and Facebook. However, he is always &lt;strong&gt;forgetting his passwords&lt;/strong&gt;. He writes the passwords down on a sheet of paper, but still sometimes struggles with logging in to his Gmail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though he is a lawyer, he is not aware of how police are inspecting devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He needs to be able to &lt;strong&gt;store sensitive data&lt;/strong&gt; safely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also needs to be able to &lt;strong&gt;transfer the data&lt;/strong&gt; securely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wants to make sure human rights defenders are not &lt;strong&gt;imprisoned&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threats&#34;&gt;Threats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His laptop, smart phone, or flash drives could be &lt;strong&gt;confiscated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the border, authorities could gain access to his devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He could be the target of &lt;strong&gt;malware&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;phishing attacks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oleksandr has &lt;strong&gt;encrypted&lt;/strong&gt; his laptop using Bitlocker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both his laptop and smart phone are &lt;strong&gt;password protected&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He knows the laws and can access &lt;strong&gt;remote IT support&lt;/strong&gt; when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens if I &lt;strong&gt;lose my password&lt;/strong&gt; again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens to all of my data if my laptop or smart phone is &lt;strong&gt;confiscated&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens if my laptop or smart phone is &lt;strong&gt;infected with malware&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
