<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>uxforum on USABLE Tools</title>
    <link>https://squiggy.github.io/tags/uxforum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in uxforum on USABLE Tools</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 11:49:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://squiggy.github.io/tags/uxforum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>USABLE Updates, Resources and more!</title>
      <link>https://squiggy.github.io/blog/2016-09-19-followingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 11:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://squiggy.github.io/blog/2016-09-19-followingup/</guid>
      <description>We can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s been two months since the UXForum! To be fair, we had a lot of sleep to catch up on, and there have been some exciting staff transitions over on our team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power to the Users -- From trainings to the UXForum and onwards.</title>
      <link>https://squiggy.github.io/blog/2016-09-15-powertotheusers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://squiggy.github.io/blog/2016-09-15-powertotheusers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three years ago, I led a digital security training for independent media in Kyiv during the peak of the EuroMaidan protests. &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/local-voices-global-change/what-good-are-secure-communications-tools-if-no-one-uses-them-690ce2bdf9ec#.hla4lsxya&#34;&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t go as planned&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This spring, we returned.  We worked with an amazingly skilled trainer who led the local &lt;a href=&#34;https://dss380.org/&#34;&gt;Digital Security School&lt;/a&gt; which had since emerged thanks to the hard work of &lt;a href=&#34;https://equalit.ie/&#34;&gt;eQualit.ie&lt;/a&gt;, and we brought together an amazing community of experts and practitioners who face complex challenges in their work as they dealt with the repercussions of the post-Maidan Ukrainian reality.  This alone would have made for a successful training; but our goal with USABLE is to scale beyond this and get to underlying problems around tool uptake.  So, we also brought a designer (who is now leading frog design&amp;rsquo;s social impact team) and a developer who led a digital security tool that the community was interested in learning more about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://squiggy.github.io/images/blog/uxforum-bigboard.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Notes on strong passwords and laptop security from the UXForum&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building this &amp;ldquo;Tool Feedback Training&amp;rdquo; approach to connecting high-risk users and tool developers through the training and design process, and the results we have already achieved, has been an amazing journey.  It may &amp;ndash; and should &amp;ndash; seem simple, but the complexities of making that precise connection is far too often presumed, but not actually done. Real people facing very specific and complex security challenges become an amorphous &amp;ldquo;they.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rdquo; needs many things from constant, bleeding-edge security improvements to changes supporting very specific use cases; but it turns out that if you actually engage the people beyond the &amp;ldquo;they&amp;rdquo; - that you learn real, often simple, changes in user experience are the path forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us for UX in a High Risk World!</title>
      <link>https://squiggy.github.io/blog/2016-06-17-uxforum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://squiggy.github.io/blog/2016-06-17-uxforum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eventbrite.com/e/ux-in-a-high-risk-world-tickets-25739389206&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; class=&#34;image fit&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://squiggy.github.io/images/uxhighrisk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;UX in a High-Risk World; Innovation Hangar, San Francisco, July 14th&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one night only, we are opening the doors to this event!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come meet the visionary leaders who are piloting and developing solutions for activists facing censorship, hacking, surveillance, and suppression in some of the world’s most challenging environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eventbrite.com/e/ux-in-a-high-risk-world-tickets-25739389206&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; class=&#34;button special&#34;&gt;RSVP Now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>